# **Rohan Dhiman**

LinkedIn: rohan-dhiman-923a21144

Address: Apt 1208, 1280 Rue Saint Marc, Montreal, QC H3H2G1 Email: rohansarnjitdhiman@gmail.com | Mobile: 438-927-9468

#### SUMMARY

Current Masters of Applied Computer Science student at Concordia University, Montreal. I have an experience of 1.5 years in FrontEnd & API development at India's largest IT Company TCS for the client State Bank Of India. I'm very interested in learning about and working with emerging digital technologies. Interested in developing a better problem-solving method for difficult tasks, as well as learning new technologies and tools as needed.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : Java, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, VB.Net, Python

**Frameworks**: React.js, Apache Hadoop, Node.js

**Databases** : MySQL, PostgreSQL

**Dev Tools**: Visual Studio, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Jupyter NoteBook, Git, Amazon AWS EC2, UiPath, Google DialogFlow,

Google Firebase

**Testing**: Unit Testing (JUnit), White Box Testing, Grey Box Testing, Black Box Testing

os : Windows, Linux, MacOS

**Methodologies**: Agile, Waterfall, Iterative methods

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Assistant System Engineer**

Tata Consultancy Services Pvt Ltd

Oct 2020 – Mar 2022

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

- Worked on the client side for State Bank Of India one of India's Largest Bank
- My role was to develop the Banks Front-End application that was used by the Branch Teller's.
- The application is being used in all the 28,000 branches across India.
- The coding languages that I have worked on were VB.NET, Java, HTML, JavaScript & XML

## **Research Analyst Intern**

Jan 2018 – Jan 2019

Organic Bots, Incubator Center

Remote – North Carolina, USA

- Worked with Robotic Process Automation, Machine Learning and Blockchain Technologies
- Worked on researching and building small applications using UiPath, Google DialogFlow and Machine Learning
- Applications that I built included a ChatBot using Google DialogFlow, UiPath Application for text scrapping automation for application form filling and Fake News Detection using Naive Bayes Algorithm.

Intern

1 June 2019 – 30 June 2019 Pune, Maharashtra, India

Sandvik Asia Pvt. Ltd

- Worked for the Industrial Project titled 'IT Asset Management System'.
- My role here was to develop in-house projects for the company which were used for the employees as well as to handle the working of the production machines used in the company.
- Coding languages that I got to work on was C Sharp (MVC Architecture).

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Concordia University**

Masters of Applied Computer Science

Course Work:

- · Programming And Problem Solving
- Advance Programming Practices
- · Distributed System Design
- BigData Analytics
- Software Design Methodologies

**Pune University** 

Montreal, Quebec, Canada . Sept 2022 – Apr 2024

Pune, Maharashtra, India Aug 2016 – Apr 2020

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

# <u>Distributed Movie Ticket Booking System</u> Java, Java RMI, User Datagram Protocol(UDP), Distributed System Design

- Designed and developed a Distributed Java application for booking of Movie tickets on three different theatre servers **Java, Java RMI and User Datagram Protocol(UDP)**
- There were three different servers created assumed for three theatres. The client and server connection was implemented using Java RMI.
- · Server to Server connectivity was established using UDP.
- The Admin user could create movie slots, remove movie slots and view the movie slots available on all servers. The customer user could book a movie ticket, cancel a movie ticket and also view the movie tickets he/she booked accross all servers.

## **Flight Ticket Booking Software**

Java, PostgreSQL, API

 Built a user friendly software to book tickets. The flight data was downloaded using the Skyscanner API and database operations were performed using PostgreSQL.

## **Covid 19 Fact Checker**

Multinomial Naive Bayes, AWS EC2, Python

• Developed a user-friendly web-based application to detect whether a news related to Covid is fake or real. The application was developed using machine learning training model **Multinomial Naïve Bayes** and was deployed on the web using **Amazon Web Services EC2**.

# **Built A ChatBot For College Library Website**

Google DialogFlow, Google Firebase

- Developed a chatbot for my college library.
- The chatbot was used to handle library-related questions from college students.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

# **Fact Check Using Multinomial Naive Bayes**

 Pradhan M.A., Shinde A., Dhiman R., Ghorpade S., Jawale S. (2021) Fact Check Using Multinomial Naive Bayes. In: Satapathy S.C., Bhateja V., Favorskaya M.N., Adilakshmi T. (eds) Smart Computing Techniques and Applications. Smart Innovation, Systems and Technologies, vol 224. Springer, Singapore. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-16-1502-3\_81

## **Fake News Detection Methods: Machine Learning Approach**

• Dr. Madhavi Ajay Pradhan, Ankita Shinde, Rohan Dhiman, Shreyas Ghorpade, Swapnil Jawale."Fake News Detection Methods: Machine Learning Approach", Volume 8, Issue VII, International Journal for Research in Applied Science and Engineering Technology (IJRASET) Page No: 971-975, ISSN: 2321-9653, https://doi.org/10.22214/ijraset.2020.29630

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

<u>Code19 Hackathon</u> Team Leader

 Won the Third Prize with a grant of \$3000 in the Motwani Jadeja Foundation Code 19 Hackathon for my final year project "Covid 19 Fact Checker".

### **Research Paper Presentation**

Presenter

 Presented our research paper titled "Fact Check Using Multinomial Naive Bayes" in the 4th INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SMART COMPUTING AND INFORMATICS (SCI-2020), Hyderabad, India.

# **Engineering Today AISSMS COE**

Technical Head

• Was chosen to be the Head for the college's Tech Fest titled Engineering Today 2019-20.